Balestasis - efficient Bayesian network learning software based on score-based learning heuristics.

version 1.02

Copyright 2017 罗良逸 ( Luo Liangyi; ルオ．りょういつ) luoliangyi@gmail.com

This software is distributed under GNU General Public License version 3 (GPLv3). Please check the COPYING file for more information.

All glory to the scientists who have contributed to the cutting-edge metrics, algorithms, and heuristics this software is based on. (Please check literature references and please include due citations should this software be used in researches.)

----------------------------

System requirement: 

	Almost any system (not necessarily x86) that supports C language and OpenMP. (OpenMP requirement can be removed or changed, if porting to other platforms is needed)

	Strongly recommend turning off hyper-threading or using a virtual machine with access to only physical cores. Balestasis might not work well with hyper-threading enabled systems.

	The memory requirement depends on the scale of network and the corresponding data set. For reference, learning from a 37-var 10000-instances data set (the Alarm network) needs around 50MB, 910-var 12000-instance (the c20ng network) needs about 300MB, 2000-var 5000-instance (Random2000-4-5000 network) needs about 5GB.
	  
	This software was confirmed being able to learn a 2000-node network from data. Learning even larger networks is theoretically possible; however, there are always software or hardware limits. 
  
Running:

	Please follow the instructions in run.sh.
	
----------------------------

Literature references for the software:

	M. Scanagatta, C. P. de Campos, G. Corani, and M. Zaffalon, Learning Bayesian Networks with Thousands of Variables, 2015 (Featured algorithms: IS, ASOBS)
	
	L. Luo, Learning Bayesian Networks using Fast Heuristics, Master's thesis, 2017 (Featured algorithm: RPGw)

	C. P. de Campos, Z. Zeng, and Q. Ji, Structure Learning of Bayesian Networks Using Constraints, 2009 (Pruning procedure)

	C. P. de Campos and Q. Ji, Efficient Structure Learning of Bayesian Networks Using Constraints, 2011 (Pruning procedure)

	H. Akaike, A New Look at the Statistical Model Identification, 1974 (AIC)

	G. Schwarz, Estimating the Dimension of a Model, 1978 (Schwarz criterion=BIC)

	J. Rissanen, Modeling By Shortest Data Description, 1978 (MDL)

	J. Suzuki, A Construction of Bayesian Networks from Databases Based on an MDL Principle, 1993 (MDL for learning Bayesian networks)

	D. Heckerman, A Tutorial on Learning With Bayesian Networks, 1995 (BIC for learning Bayesian networks)

